Welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. Topic 2.4 is all about the
transatlantic trade. The main thing to
take away from all of this is all
Europeans really wanted from the New
World was profit. Crops in the New World
were so unbelievably profitable by the
Europeans that heck, there's an argument
that without the crop of sugar, there is
no African slave trade. And as goods and
slaves were being transported, a system
of trade known as the triangular trade
where European ships carried
manufactured goods such as guns, cloth
and alcohol to Africa in exchange for
African slaves to be transported to the
New World and have them undergo the
middle passage which saw Africans
chained and tightly cramped together in
ships to the New World. And finally in
the Americas, the enslaved Africans were
sold and the ships were loaded with raw
materials such as sugar, tobacco, and
cotton, which were then transported back
to Europe. As you can see, this way of
trade resembles a triangle, which is why
it's known as the triangular trade. This
trade would also cause diseases like
smallpox to be spread to the New World
and syphilis to be spread to Europe.
Meanwhile, in North American colonies,
the British government continuously
attempted to incorporate their
monarchical and hierarchical structure
in the colonies for the point of earning
the most wealth, which would inevitably
receive pushback from the colonists and
the American Indians with one such
example being the Bacon's Rebellion
where after the governor of Virginia
refused to expel the Native Americans
from Virginia, a man named Nathaniel
Bacon rebelled and with a group of
around 400 followers tried to overturn
that decision and killed the natives.
Although the British suppressed this
rebellion, it highlighted the potential
for colonists to revolt, foreshadowing
the larger conflicts that would lead to
the American Revolution. On the screen
now are questions for this topic. Pause
now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
See you in the next one.